<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>on Rosalie de Winther</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in on Rosalie de Winther</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Master's degree on volumetric rendering @ Traverse Research</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/master-degree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/master-degree/</guid><description>&lt;p>To finish the Game and Media Technology master&amp;rsquo;s program I obviously had to write and defend a thesis. I was very lucky to be able to do this in collaboration with &lt;a href="https://traverse.nl/">Traverse Research&lt;/a>, and work on some awesome tech. During this time I ventured into the wonderful world of volumetric rendering, with &lt;a href="https://x.com/emiliolaiso">Emilio Laiso&lt;/a>. I worked on the data structure, which ended up being largely inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.openvdb.org/">VDB&lt;/a>. And Emilio did the shading. Of course with plentiful collaboration when we could help each other out. During this time I also got to present my work which was an amazing opportunity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Advanced Graphics @UU</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/advanced-graphics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/advanced-graphics/</guid><description>&lt;p>This course was one of the major reasons why I wanted to do my master&amp;rsquo;s at Utrecht University, and it delivered. For the first time, I could work on a ray tracer with the help of a very good and dedicated lecturer, namely &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/j_bikker">Jacco Bikker&lt;/a>. During the course, we first implemented a Whitted style ray tracer (on the CPU). I was pleasantly surprised with the performance, as I thought nothing could be rendered (let alone ray traced) on the CPU. In the scene below you see most of the implemented effects, reflection, refraction, directional lights, point lights, beer&amp;rsquo;s law, vignetting, anti aliasing, gamma correction and chromatic aberration.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Voxels</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/voxels/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/voxels/</guid><description>&lt;p>As quite some people do, I got inspired by &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1R5WFZk86kE">John Lin&amp;rsquo;s voxel engine&lt;/a> and thus, got started researching how voxels work. At first, I started with a meshing based approach similar to minecraft and got some basic lighting going. One of the first real issues I encountered was with transparency, as I did not have much experience with graphics I did not realize it would be such a hassle to render transparent water for example.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Principal component analysis of League of Legends Champions</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/principal-component-analysis-of-league-of-legends-champions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/principal-component-analysis-of-league-of-legends-champions/</guid><description>&lt;p>League of Legends is a popular 5 vs 5 game where matches last between 20 and 40 minutes (usually) and you can choose to play any out of 150+ champions, each differing in play style, strengths and weaknesses. Most players have a certain play style or champion which they prefer, while some just play whatever they feel like playing. Since I regularly play League with my friends and was stuck deciding which champion I should play next, I did a principal component analysis based on data scraped from a popular League statistics website named &lt;a href="https://lolalytics.com/">lolalytics&lt;/a>. Below, you can see a visualization of the first two principal components. If you find your favorite champion, you can see which champions are similar and maybe give them a try as well. For me, as a fiddlesticks player, I should try Elise for example. (I know it&amp;rsquo;s completely unreadable on this page, but the resolution is quite high, so you can zoom in)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Drone follow @HU</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/drone-follow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/drone-follow/</guid><description>&lt;p>For this assignment, we were meant to use PID systems in some form to control movement in the real world. So me, being stuck in my room during a corona lock down, had no hardware in my house besides a &lt;a href="https://www.ryzerobotics.com/tello">Tello drone&lt;/a>. Due to this, I was basically forced to implement a PID controller for each of the 4 degrees of freedom of the drone. This allowed for quite fine-grained control of the drone, even in small spaces, such as my room. To make it more interactive I decided to have it follow some object, and as a QR code can be well detected and is perfectly square, I decided to go with this. The distance from the drone to the QR code can be calculated when you know the size of the QR code on the screen and the field of view of the camera. The rotation can be measured using the difference in length of the left and right side of the qr code. These two, along with the offsets from the camera center, are the foundation of the PID input. Below is a video demonstrating the result.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Real time strategy game @HU</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/rts-game/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/posts/rts-game/</guid><description>&lt;p>During the 2nd year of my bachelor, me and five others made a real time strategy (RTS) game. The assignment was to make a game (without the use of a full game engine), and as we all enjoyed Age of Empires, we decided to make an RTS. We thought this would be an interesting challenge as it required an enemy who would autonomously control their units. Furthermore, it required additional path finding AI for all units. Some gameplay can be seen below. Resources are being collected, units being trained, buildings being built and enemies being defeated, with some speedups in between.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a software engineer at &lt;a href="https://traverse.nl/">Traverse Research in Breda&lt;/a>, with a focus on graphics. Before this I did a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Game and Media Technology at Utrecht University, a minor in Data Science at Technical University Eindhoven, a bachelor in Computer Engineering at HU University of Applied Sciences. Besides this I have done internships at &lt;a href="https://www.vicarvision.nl/">VicarVision&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.sentient.nl/">Sentient Information systems&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In my spare time I enjoy skating, programming, calisthenics, cooking and playing/analyzing games.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rosaliedewinther.github.io/contact/</guid><description>&lt;p>You can contact find me in the following places:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Discord: derosalie&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email: &lt;a href="mailto:rosaliedewinther@gmail.com">rosaliedewinther@gmail.com&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Github: &lt;a href="https://github.com/rosaliedewinther">Rosalie de Winther&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Twitter: &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/R__Winther">@R__Winther&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>